ARNOLD BRECHT PAPERS (GER024) 1865-1974
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Correspondence, 1905-1976; 2; 319 file folders
  - General correspondence, 2.2
    - Demeter, Karl, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Deutsche Verlags-Anstalt, Stuttgart, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Dimrock, Marshall E. (Immigration and Naturalization Service), 1940-1961 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Donnell, Dorothy, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Dorn, Herbert, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Dorpalen, Andreas, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Dotzauer, Dina, 1957-1963 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - ds production (Dieter Schmidt), 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Duarte, Paulo (Anhembi, Saõ Paulo), 1962 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Duggan, Stephen, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Duncan, John Paul, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Durham, Henry C., 1956-1957; 1976 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Dunner, Joseph, 1945-1946; 1962-1965 (Box 3, Folder 60)
      Including Brecht's contributions to the Dictionary of Political Science.
    - E -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Ebenstein, William, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Eberhard, F., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Eckardt, Wolfram von, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Eckener, Hugo, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Ehrmann, Henry W., 1945-1973 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Einstein, Albert, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Emge, Carl A., 1948; 1954 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Engisch, Karl, 1957-1972 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - English, Raymond, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Erdmann, Karl Dietrich, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Erler, Adalbert, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Eschenberg, Theodor, 1953-1976 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Esslinger, William, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Ewers, Hans, 1959; 1962 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Eynern, Margarete von, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - F -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Fackelträger Verlag, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Fairman, Charles, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Faul, Erwin, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Fay, Sidney B., 1942 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Fehling, Jürgen, 1905-1968 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Feiler, Marie, 1953-1971 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Fetscher, Iring, Undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Finer, Herman, 1943-1948 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Flechtheim, Julius & Helene, 1949-1972 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Fleming, William, 1960-1963 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Flemming, Arthur S., 1952 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Flotow, Rose Marie von, Undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Forkosch, Morris, 1951-1975 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, 1952; 1960 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Freund, Ludwig, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Frick, Heinrich, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Fried, John H. E., 1960 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Friedman, Bruno, 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Friedrich, Carl Joachim (Achim), 1934-1971 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Friedrich, Manfred, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Fritzsche, Klaus, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Fritz, Kurt & Louise von, 1953-1972 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - G -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Gaus, John M., 1940-1954 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Gillespie, S. Hazard & Ruth, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Globus, Joseph & Grete, 1946; 1955 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Glum, Friedrich, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Goldsmith, Arthur J., 1941 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Goldstein, Naomi, Wayland Vaughan, Gordon Allport, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Gotthard, Walther & Helene, 1949-1968 (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Grabowsky, Adolf, 1941; 1956-1961 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Grathoff, Richard, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Gray, McGregor, 1961-1968 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Gropius, Walter & Ilse, Undated; 1974 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Grossmann, Kurt R., 1950-1960 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Grunebaum, L. H., 1940-1956 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Grzesinski, Albert C. (Association of Free Germans Inc), 1942 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Guenther, Peter W., 1958 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Gumbel, [Emil J.], 1952 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Gunst, Dietrich, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Guradze, Heinz, 1959-1972 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Gurwitsch, Aron, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - György, Antalffy, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - H -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Haig, Robert M., 1940-1949 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Hallowell, John H., 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Hamburger, Ernest, 1943-1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Hartmann, Heinz & Dora, 1954-1971 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Harvard Law Review, 1941-1950 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Harvard University, 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Haskell, Henry S., 1934 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Haussmann, Conrad, 1921 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Haussmann, Hermann, 1948-1950 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Hazard, John N., 1947-1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Heard, Alexander, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Hebal, John J., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Heberle, Rudolf, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Heimann, Hugo, 1944; 1949 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Heimpel, Hermann, 1956; 1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Heller, Gertrud, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Helmolt, Bernd von, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Henle, G., 1955 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Hennig, E., 1967; 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Hennis, Wilhelm, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Hermens, Ferdinand A., 1942-1977 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Herring, E. Pendleton, 1938; 1954 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Herrmann, Gertrude, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Herz, Else, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Herz, John H., 1953 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Hesse, Artur (Gewerkschaft Deutscher Beamtenbund), 1949-1956 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Carl Heymanns Verlag KG, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Hippel, Fritz von, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Hirsch, Felix E., 1944-1976 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Hirsch, Julius, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Hocke, Gustav René, 1934; 1949 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Hocking, (William) Ernest, 1940-1965 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Höpker-Aschoff, Hermann, 1934-1952 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Holborn, Hajo, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Holcombe, Arthur N., 1938-1956 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Holmes, John H., 1949 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Hook, Sidney, 1963; 1969 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - I - J -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Igel, Konrad (concerning Walther Rathenau), 1943-1962 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - International Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Iwand, Hans / Gurian, [Waldemar], 1952 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Jackh, Ernest, 1945; 1948 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Jacobsohn, Peter S., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Jaffe, Emy, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Jaffe-Richthofen, Else, 1959-1966 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Janovsky, Hannah Salomon, 1967; 1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Jellinek, Walter, 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Junz, Alfred J., 1950-1964; 1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - K -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Kann, Robert A., 1947 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Kaufmann, Felix & Else, 1946-1950 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Kaufmann, Walter H., 1950; 1953 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Kelsen, Hans, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Kemble, E. D. (General Electric Company), 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Smiddy, Harold F. "Research -- And Shaping the Future of Management", Undated; typescript (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Kempner, Robert M. W., 1941-1947; 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Kennan, George, 1952; 1957 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Kessler, Friedrich, Undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Kiepenheuer & Witsch (Verlag), 1965 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Kirchheimer, Anne, 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Klepper, Otto, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - New England Christian Committee for Refugees, Undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Kline, Reamer ( Bard College), 1961; 1963 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Knieriem, August von, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Koch-Weser, Erich & Irma, 1942-1967 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Kohn, Hans, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Kohn, Walter S. G., 1957-1971 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Kolbe, Dieter (concerning Erwin Bumke), 1971 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Krayer, Otto & Ruth, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Külz (Senatspräsident beim Bundesverwaltungsgericht), 1958-1959 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Kürschners Gelehrtenkalender, 1959; 1968 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Kunkel, Wolfgang, 1949-1950; 1955 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Kutscher, Irmgard & Hans, 1953-1973 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - L -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Lambie, Morris B., ca. 1940s (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Landau, Martin, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Lang, Reginald D., 1946 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Lasswell, Harold D., 1942; 1962 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Lazar, Joseph, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Lederer, Gertrud, 1958; 1960 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Leibholz, Gerhard, 1953-1959 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Lepawsky, Albert, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Leser, Norbert, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Leval, Hilde Peltzer, 1959-1967 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Leyden, Victor von, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Liang, His-Huey, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Lichtenstein, Walter, 1937-1946 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Liebman, Charles J. (Refugee Economic Corporation), 1946 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Lindheim, Hermann von, 1952-1955 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Lins, Mario, ca. 1970s (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Lippincott, Benjamin E., 1947; 1966 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Lippmann, Walter, 1941; 1950; 1952 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Litchfield, Edward H., 1945; 1949-1954 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Litt, Theo, 1939-1962 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Littauer, Lucius N., 1941 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Loewenstein, Karl, 1941-1947; 1972 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Löwith, Karl, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Lohmann, Friedrich, 1951; 1966 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Luckemeyer, Ludwig, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Luther, Hans, 1934; 1955; 1957 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - M -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Mack, Arien (Social Research), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Macmahon, Arthur W., 1942-1947 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Macridis, Roy C., 1953 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Mainzer, Otto, 1941; 1947 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Mann, Golo, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Mann, Katia, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Mann, Thomas / Fritz Behn, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Marburg, Gertrude (Mrs. Louis C), 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Maritain, Jacques, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Martin, John, 1938-1953 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Marx, Hugo, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Marx, Werner, 1958-1972 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Mason, Lester B., 1946; 1952 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Mattern, Hans W., 1941 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - McClelland, Charles A., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - McCollum, Dudley F., 1934 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - McLachlan, Donald, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Mehnert, Klaus, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Melamid, Alexander, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Mende, Dietrich, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Menzel, Hans & Emmy (née Severing), 1947-1963 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Menzel, Christiane, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Merriam, Charles E., 1936-1940 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Mestern, Hans, 1951-1957 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Meyer, Eugene, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Miller, Susanne, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Mirkine-Guetzévitch, Boris & Eugenia, 1946-1956 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Montaño, Salvador M. Dana, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Morgenthau, Hans J., 1950 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Morstein-Marx, Fritz, 1936-1965 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Müller, Hildegard & Hans, 1961-1965 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Müller-Seidel, Walter, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Munro, Dana G., 1944-1946 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Murmann, Ernst, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - Musgrave, Richard A., 1948 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - N, O -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Nash, Arnold, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Nass, Otto, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Natanson, Maurice, 1963; 1968 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - The National Archives (Dorsey W. Hyde Jr), 1941 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Needler, Martin, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Die Neue Zeitung, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Neumann, Sigmund, 1944-1953 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Newman, K. J., 1960 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Norddeutscher Rundfunk, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Nymphenburger Verlagshandlung, 1953-1963 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Odum, Howard W., 1942-1943 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Ogg, Frederic A. (American Political Science Review), 1934-1947 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Ohmann, Fritz Ernst, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Oldenburg, Otto, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Oppen, Beate Ruhm von, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Oppenheim, Felix, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - P -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Paeschke, Hans (Merkur), 1967 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Palitsch, Alice, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Paul, Julius, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Pelckmann, Horst, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Peltzer, Artur, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Peltzer, Bert, 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Peltzer, Helmut, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Pennock, J. Roland, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Perry, Ralph Barton (American Defense, Harvard Group), 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Peters, Hans, 1949; 1959 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Pfuhl, Georg & Erika, 1915-1968 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Pfuhl, Sophia, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Pikart, Eberhard, 1955-1956; 1965; 1970 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - R. Piper et Co. Verlag (Walter Hinderer), 1963 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Planck, Erwin, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Plessner, Monika, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Poetzsch-Heffter, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Pogge-von Strandmann, Hartmut, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Pollock, James K., 1945-1955 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Popitz, Heinrich, 1972; Undated (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Posner, Ernst, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - Pound, Roscoe, 1939-1941 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Public Personnel Review (J. J. Donovan), 1950-1951 (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - R -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Radbruch, Gustav, 1939-1949 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Radbruch, Lydia, 1950-1972 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Rademacher, Hans, 1941; 1951; 1969 (death notice) (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Radin, Max (California Law Review), 1939-1940 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Radio Bremen, 1959-1962 (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Rauers, Friedrich, 1953-1954 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Recaséns-Siches, Luis, 1955-1961 (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Redslob, Edwin, 1948-1972 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Reed, Edward A., 1970 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Reed, Ruth Lawrence, Undated (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Rempel, Rudolf, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - Richter, Thomas J., 1951-1952 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Ridgeway, George, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Rieppel, Eva, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Riesman, David, 1939; 1941 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Riezler, Kurt, 1943; 1952 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Riezler, Walter, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Riggs, Fred W., 1964 (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - Rintelen, Paul & Anita, 1955-1957 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Robinson, James A., 1961 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Rodriguez, Fausto E. (Luis Recaséns-Siches Festschrift), 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Rogers, Lindsay, 1937-1950 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Roothbert, Albert & Toni, 1944-1969 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Rothfels, Hans, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Rüstow, Alexander, 1952-1963 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Rüstow, Lorena, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Runde, Wolfgang & Antje, 1954-1960 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Rutz, Consuelo, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - S -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Samuel, Arthur, 1964-1967 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Schaeffer, Hans & Eva, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Schaffner, Joseph Halle, 1939; 1951-1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Schaffner, Ruth, 1967-1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Schairer, Reinhold, 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Schatz, Rudolf, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Scherk, Gerhard & Elizabeth, 1950-1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Schiffer, Eugen, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Schlesinger, M., 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Schlesinger, Rudolf B. (Columbia Law Review), 1941 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Schmidt, Eberhard, 1960-1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Schmidt, Hans Martin, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Schmidt, Robert H., 1959; 1963 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Schmidt-Klugmann, Annemarie, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Schmidt-Römhild, Georg, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Schneider, Hans, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Schönwandt, M., 1957-1961 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Schroeder, Hans, 1944-1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Schröter, Walter, 1962; 1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Schüller, Richard, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Schulz, Gerhard, 1957-1965 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Schulze, Hagen, 1968-1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Schwenk, Walter, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Schwertfeger, Bernhard, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Seligman, Edwin R., 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Severing, Carl, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Shuster, George N., 1944 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Siebeck, Hans Goerg (J.C.B. Mohr, Paul Siebeck), 1963; 1975 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Sösemann, Bernd W., 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Sollmann, William, 1937-1951 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Sontheimer, Kurt, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Spangenberg, Berthold (Nymphenburger Verlagshandlung), 1959-1964 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - SPD (Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands), 1952; 1958 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Speyer, Emil John, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Spiegelberg, Ernst (Ernest) & Marie-Louise, 1943-1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Spranger, Eduard, 1954-1958 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Staatslexikon (Herder Verlag), 1957; 1959 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Stadelmeyer, Peter (Goethe House, NY), 1967; 1972 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Stampfer, Friedrich, 1945-1947 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Stern, Frederick M., 1945; 1972 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Sternberger, Dolf, 1955-1968 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Stinnes, Edmund H., 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Stoke, Harold W., 1946 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Stolper, Gustav, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Stolper, Toni, 1956-1972 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Stourzh, Gerald, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Strauss, Leo, 1941-1972 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Strauss, Walter, 1950; 1954 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Strausz-Hupé, Robert, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Stuttgarter Zeitung, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Süddeutsche Zeitung, 1950; 1955 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Süddeutscher Rundfunk, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - T - V -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Tillich, Paul, 1943; 1959 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Tillich, Hannah, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Topitsch, Ernst, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Ulich, Robert, 1934; 1941-1944 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - University of Heidelberg (Universität Heidelberg), 1947-1963 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - University of Mainz (Universität Mainz), 1947 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Unkelbach, Helmut, 1956-1968 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Vagts, Alfred, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Valentin, 1942; 1946 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Valle, Raymond, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Verdross, Alfred, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Vermehren, Kurt, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Viehweg, Theodor, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Voegelin, Eric / Voegelin Festschrift, 1946-1962 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Vogelstein, T.M., 1940 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Vogt, Martin, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Volkamer, Gustav, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - W - Z -- miscellaneous correspondence, Undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Wachenheim, Hedwig, 1943; 1958-1967 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Warburg, Eric M., 1946-1975 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Warburg, Max, 1936-1944 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Warburg, Ingrid, Undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Weber, Alfred, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Weber, Dieter, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Weil, Agnes (Mrs. Sumner), 1964-1972 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Weishaupt, Paul, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Weiszäcker, Carl Friedrich von, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Weltner (née Reuter), Maria (Mia), 1951-1962 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Wever, Karl, 1948-1960 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Weyland, Hans, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Wheeler-Bennett, Sir John W., 1937; 1971 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - White, Leonard D., 1936-1945; 1954 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Widder, Erwin, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Wiese, Leopold von, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Wildenmann, Rudolf, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Williams, Pierce, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Wilson, Francis G., 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Winckelmann, Johannes, 1958-1967 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Wissell, Rudolf, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Wolf, Erik, 1955-1959 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Wolfers, Arnold, 1944-1954 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Wolff, Ernst, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Wolman, Benjamin B. (Cross Currents of Our Times), 1967 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Woodrow Wilson Foundation / Woodrow Wilson Award, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Wright, Benjamin, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Wright, Quincy, 1949-1952 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Zahn, Karl von, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Zahn-Harnack, Agnes von, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - "Important letters received". Transcripts, 1934-1946 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence concerning published articles, 1934-1957; 1966 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Correspondence concerning lecture engagements, 1933-1967 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Students: A -- B, Undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Students: C -- F, Undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Students: Eugene T. Ferraro, Undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Students: G -- J, Undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Students: K -- L, Undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Students: M -- R, Undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Students: S -- Z, Undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Students, other, Undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Correspondence with U.S. government officials, 2.3
    - U.S. government officials, 1936-1961 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Acheson, Dean, 1949; 1952 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Adams, Sherman, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Appleby, Paul H., 1941-1946 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Carter, Jimmy & Rosalynn, Undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Clay, Lucius D., 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Dulles, John Foster, 1934-1957 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Frankfurter, Felix, 1937-1950 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Fulbright, J. W., 1952-2953 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Hoover, Herbert C., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Hull, Cordell, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Jessup, Philip C., 1946-1952 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Jump, W. A., 1939-1945 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Lewis, Geoffrey W., 1952-1957 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Murphy, Robert, 1947-1957 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Patton, George S., 1945 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1952 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1944; 1946 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Rusk, Dean, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Stone, Donald C., 1940-1960 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Wertheimer, Egon Ranshofen, 1942-1946 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - New York City/State officials, 1938-1942; 1963 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - United Nations officials, 1946-1947; 1950-1961 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - War Department members (Allen L. Edwards, Paul M. A. Linebarger), 1942-1959 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - OMGUS (Office of Military Government for Germany), including, 2.7
    - Glaser, Comstock, 1939-1951 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Jones, Howard P., 1943-1946 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Karsen, Fritz, 1943-1947 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - OMGUS (Office of Military Government for Germany), including, 2.8
    - Landin, Harold W., 1948 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Tuthill, John & Erna, 1945-1948; 1962 (Box 5, Folder 65)
    - Warner, Adolphe J., 1947 (Box 5, Folder 65)